var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "وَإِبْرَاهِيمَ",
        "answer": "And Ibrahim",
        "pcklId": "64",
        "rootWordId": 6,
        "tlit": "wa-ib'rāhīma",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِبْرَاهِيمَ الَّذِي وَفَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِبْرَاهِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "Ibrahim",
        "waznTlit": "ib'rāhīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 69,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَآبَاؤُكُمْ",
        "answer": "and your forefathers",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "waābāukum",
        "frequency": 117,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا أَسْمَاءٌ سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 64,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِثْمِ",
        "answer": "sins",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 16,
        "tlit": "l-ith'mi",
        "frequency": 48,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ث م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِثْم",
        "waznEnglish": "sin",
        "waznTlit": "ith'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أُخْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "another",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "ukh'rā",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَآهُ نَزْلَةً أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the other",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ukh'rā",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَنَاةَ الثَّالِثَةَ الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أُخْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "(of) another",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "ukh'rā",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَّا تَزِرُ وَازِرَةٌ وِزْرَ أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "another",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ukh'rā",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ عَلَيْهِ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرَةُ",
        "answer": "(is) the last",
        "pcklId": "209",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhiratu",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلِلَّهِ الْآخِرَةُ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 155,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْآخِرَةِ",
        "answer": "in the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "210",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "bil-ākhirati",
        "frequency": 250,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 155,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "223",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ يَغْشَى السِّدْرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذْ",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "224",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِذْ",
        "answer": "and when",
        "pcklId": "225",
        "rootWordId": 26,
        "tlit": "wa-idh",
        "frequency": 239,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 19,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ وَإِذْ أَنْتُمْ أَجِنَّةٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِذ",
        "rootWordType": "time adverb",
        "wazn": "إِذ",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idh",
        "waznType": "Time adverb",
        "waznFreq": 239,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "311",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": 409,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّجْمِ إِذَا هَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 409,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "when",
        "pcklId": "312",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": 409,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ إِذَا تُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 409,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذًا",
        "answer": "then",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 28,
        "tlit": "idhan",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " تِلْكَ إِذًا قِسْمَةٌ ضِيزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِذًا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِذًا",
        "waznEnglish": "then",
        "waznTlit": "idhan",
        "waznType": "Particle (Surprise particle)",
        "waznFreq": 31,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَأْذَنَ",
        "answer": "Allah has given permission",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 29,
        "tlit": "yadhana",
        "frequency": 102,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ذ ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَذِنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to permit",
        "waznTlit": "adhina",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 23,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "409",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍi",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِلَّهِ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الْأَرْضِ لِيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسَاءُوا",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "the earth",
        "pcklId": "410",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "l-arḍi",
        "frequency": 461,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 18,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ وَإِذْ أَنْتُمْ أَجِنَّةٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 461,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَزِفَتِ",
        "answer": "Has approached",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 37,
        "tlit": "azifati",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 57,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَزِفَتِ الْآزِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ز ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَزِفَتِ",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach",
        "waznTlit": "azifati",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآزِفَةُ",
        "answer": "the Approaching Day",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 37,
        "tlit": "l-āzifatu",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 57,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَزِفَتِ الْآزِفَةُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ز ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَازِفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "approaching",
        "waznTlit": "āzifat",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْأُفُقِ",
        "answer": "(was) in the horizon ",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 51,
        "tlit": "bil-ufuqi",
        "frequency": 3,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَهُوَ بِالْأُفُقِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ف ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ف ق",
        "waznEnglish": "horizon",
        "waznTlit": "hamza fā qāf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْمُؤْتَفِكَةَ",
        "answer": "And the overturned cities",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 52,
        "tlit": "wal-mu'tafikata",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْمُؤْتَفِكَةَ أَهْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ف ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْتَفِكَة",
        "waznEnglish": "overturned cities",
        "waznTlit": "mu'tafikat",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "(is) except",
        "pcklId": "508",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هُوَ إِلَّا وَحْيٌ يُوحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "(are) except",
        "pcklId": "509",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا أَسْمَاءٌ سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "510",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 16,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَمَا تَهْوَى الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "511",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "512",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "513",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "514",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "515",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": 663,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَيْسَ لِلْإِنْسَانِ إِلَّا مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)",
        "waznFreq": 663,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1273",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1274",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسَاءُوا بِمَا عَمِلُوا",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "those who",
        "pcklId": "1275",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَحْسَنُوا بِالْحُسْنَى",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "Those who",
        "pcklId": "1276",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhīna",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "the one who",
        "pcklId": "1277",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الَّذِي",
        "answer": "who",
        "pcklId": "1278",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "alladhī",
        "frequency": 1464,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِبْرَاهِيمَ الَّذِي وَفَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)",
        "waznFreq": 1464,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "has Allah sent down",
        "pcklId": "2559",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ مَا أَنْزَلَ اللَّهُ بِهَا مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَلِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "But for Allah",
        "pcklId": "2560",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "falillahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلِلَّهِ الْآخِرَةُ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah has given permission",
        "pcklId": "2561",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَلِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "And for Allah",
        "pcklId": "2562",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "walillahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِلَّهِ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2563",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لَهَا مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ كَاشِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلَّهِ",
        "answer": "to Allah",
        "pcklId": "2564",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "lillahi",
        "frequency": 2851,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْجُدُوا لِلَّهِ وَاعْبُدُوا",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 2699,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آلَاءِ",
        "answer": "the Favors",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 62,
        "tlit": "ālāi",
        "frequency": 37,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ آلَاءِ رَبِّكَ تَتَمَارَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَالَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "favor, bounty",
        "waznTlit": "ālā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 34,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "660",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَوْحَىٰ إِلَىٰ عَبْدِهِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "661",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": 742,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition",
        "waznFreq": 742,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لِلْإِنْسَانِ مَا تَمَنَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "Or",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": 137,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَمْ يُنَبَّأْ بِمَا فِي صُحُفِ مُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction",
        "waznFreq": 137,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أُمَّهَاتِكُمْ",
        "answer": "(of) your mothers",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "ummahātikum",
        "frequency": 119,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 24,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِذْ أَنْتُمْ أَجِنَّةٌ فِي بُطُونِ أُمَّهَاتِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُمّ",
        "waznEnglish": "mother, foundation, final abode",
        "waznTlit": "umm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "answer": "believe",
        "pcklId": "491",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "yu'minūna",
        "frequency": 879,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 537,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "answer": "the female",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "l-unthā",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَكُمُ الذَّكَرُ وَلَهُ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "answer": "(of) female",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "l-unthā",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the female",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "wal-unthā",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ خَلَقَ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْإِنْسَانِ",
        "answer": "(is) for man",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "lil'insāni",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لِلْإِنْسَانِ مَا تَمَنَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 71,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِلْإِنْسَانِ",
        "answer": "for man",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "lil'insāni",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَيْسَ لِلْإِنْسَانِ إِلَّا مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 71,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the first",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "wal-ūlā",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 25,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلِلَّهِ الْآخِرَةُ وَالْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ أَهْلَكَ عَادًا الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the former",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": 170,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نَذِيرٌ مِنَ النُّذُرِ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 82,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "(of) Abode",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 87,
        "tlit": "l-mawā",
        "frequency": 36,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَهَا جَنَّةُ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَأْوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "I will betake myself",
        "waznTlit": "mawā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 22,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "آيَاتِ",
        "answer": "(the) Signs",
        "pcklId": "364",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "āyāti",
        "frequency": 382,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَدْ رَأَىٰ مِنْ آيَاتِ رَبِّهِ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 382,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَصَرُ",
        "answer": "the sight",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "l-baṣaru",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا زَاغَ الْبَصَرُ وَمَا طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 48,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بُطُونِ",
        "answer": "(the) wombs",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 136,
        "tlit": "buṭūni",
        "frequency": 25,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 23,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ وَإِذْ أَنْتُمْ أَجِنَّةٌ فِي بُطُونِ أُمَّهَاتِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) concealed",
        "waznTlit": "baṭn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بَعْدِ",
        "answer": "after",
        "pcklId": "138",
        "rootWordId": 139,
        "tlit": "baʿdi",
        "frequency": 235,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَمْ مِنْ مَلَكٍ فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ع د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَعْد",
        "waznEnglish": "was long",
        "waznTlit": "baʿd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 199,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَبْقَىٰ",
        "answer": "He spared",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 150,
        "tlit": "abqā",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 51,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَثَمُودَ فَمَا أَبْقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَقِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remain",
        "waznTlit": "baqiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَبْكُونَ",
        "answer": "weep",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 153,
        "tlit": "tabkūna",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَضْحَكُونَ وَلَا تَبْكُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ك ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to weep",
        "waznTlit": "bakat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَبْكَىٰ",
        "answer": "and makes (one) weep",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 153,
        "tlit": "wa-abkā",
        "frequency": 7,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَضْحَكَ وَأَبْكَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ب ك ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبْكَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make weep",
        "waznTlit": "abkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَبْلَغُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) their sum",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "mablaghuhum",
        "frequency": 77,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ مَبْلَغُهُمْ مِنَ الْعِلْمِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَبْلَغ",
        "waznEnglish": "reaches",
        "waznTlit": "mablagh",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَّبِعُونَ",
        "answer": "they follow",
        "pcklId": "153",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "yattabiʿūna",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَمَا تَهْوَى الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَّبِعُونَ",
        "answer": "they follow",
        "pcklId": "154",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "yattabiʿūna",
        "frequency": 172,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 136,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الثَّالِثَةَ",
        "answer": "the third",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 206,
        "tlit": "l-thālithata",
        "frequency": 32,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 20,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَنَاةَ الثَّالِثَةَ الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ث ل ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ثَّالِثَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(is the) third",
        "waznTlit": "thālithat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لِيَجْزِيَ",
        "answer": "that He may recompense",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "liyajziya",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسَاءُوا بِمَا عَمِلُوا",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَجْزِيَ",
        "answer": "and recompense",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "wayajziya",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَحْسَنُوا بِالْحُسْنَى",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُجْزَاهُ",
        "answer": "he will be recompensed for it",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "yuj'zāhu",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ يُجْزَاهُ الْجَزَاءَ الْأَوْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reward, to recompense",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 73,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَزَاءَ",
        "answer": "the recompense",
        "pcklId": "106",
        "rootWordId": 245,
        "tlit": "l-jazāa",
        "frequency": 118,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ يُجْزَاهُ الْجَزَاءَ الْأَوْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ز ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَزَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "avail",
        "waznTlit": "jazā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 42,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَجْتَنِبُونَ",
        "answer": "avoid",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 263,
        "tlit": "yajtanibūna",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱجْتَنَبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avoid",
        "waznTlit": "ij'tanabu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجِنَّةٌ",
        "answer": "fetuses",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "ajinnatun",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 21,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ وَإِذْ أَنْتُمْ أَجِنَّةٌ فِي بُطُونِ أُمَّهَاتِكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجِنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "ajinnat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّةُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Garden",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannatu",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَهَا جَنَّةُ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 147,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "has come to them",
        "pcklId": "255",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāahum",
        "frequency": 278,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 22,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنْ رَبِّهِمُ الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 278,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَدِيثِ",
        "answer": "statement",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 297,
        "tlit": "l-ḥadīthi",
        "frequency": 36,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَمِنْ هَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ تَعْجَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح د ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَدِيث",
        "waznEnglish": "Do you tell them",
        "waznTlit": "ḥadīth",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَحْسَنُوا",
        "answer": "do good",
        "pcklId": "21",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "aḥsanū",
        "frequency": 194,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَحْسَنُوا بِالْحُسْنَى",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْسَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do good",
        "waznTlit": "aḥsana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحُسْنَى",
        "answer": "with the best",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 321,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥus'nā",
        "frequency": 194,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 16,
        "arabicAyah": " وَيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَحْسَنُوا بِالْحُسْنَى",
        "rootWord": "ح س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُسْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "And excellent",
        "waznTlit": "ḥus'nā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "the truth",
        "pcklId": "267",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "l-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": 287,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 15,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 247,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَحْيَا",
        "answer": "and gives life",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "wa-aḥyā",
        "frequency": 184,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَمَاتَ وَأَحْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to give life",
        "waznTlit": "aḥyā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 51,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَيَاةَ",
        "answer": "the life",
        "pcklId": "165",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "l-ḥayata",
        "frequency": 184,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَيَوٰة",
        "waznEnglish": "you will live",
        "waznTlit": "ḥayat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقَ",
        "answer": "created",
        "pcklId": "146",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqa",
        "frequency": 261,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ خَلَقَ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 184,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَدَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and came down",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 481,
        "tlit": "fatadallā",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ دَنَا فَتَدَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَدَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come down",
        "waznTlit": "tadallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "دَنَا",
        "answer": "he approached",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "danā",
        "frequency": 133,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 8,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ دَنَا فَتَدَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَنَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to approach, to draw",
        "waznTlit": "danā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "nearer",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "adnā",
        "frequency": 133,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَ قَابَ قَوْسَيْنِ أَوْ أَدْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَدْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "adnā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الدُّنْيَا",
        "answer": "(of) the world",
        "pcklId": "82",
        "rootWordId": 488,
        "tlit": "l-dun'yā",
        "frequency": 133,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "د ن و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دُّنْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to draw",
        "waznTlit": "dun'yā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 115,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "دُونِ",
        "answer": "besides",
        "pcklId": "128",
        "rootWordId": 497,
        "tlit": "dūni",
        "frequency": 144,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لَهَا مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ كَاشِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "د و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د و ن",
        "waznEnglish": "other than",
        "waznTlit": "dāl wāw nūn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 144,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذَّكَرُ",
        "answer": "the male",
        "pcklId": "169",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhakaru",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 21,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَكُمُ الذَّكَرُ وَلَهُ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhakar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الذَّكَرَ",
        "answer": "the male",
        "pcklId": "170",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhakara",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ خَلَقَ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhakar",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ذِكْرِنَا",
        "answer": "Our Reminder",
        "pcklId": "255",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "dhik'rinā",
        "frequency": 292,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'r",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَأَىٰ",
        "answer": "it saw",
        "pcklId": "212",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "raā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا كَذَبَ الْفُؤَادُ مَا رَأَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "he saw",
        "pcklId": "213",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَتُمَارُونَهُ عَلَىٰ مَا يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَآهُ",
        "answer": "he saw him",
        "pcklId": "214",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "raāhu",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَآهُ نَزْلَةً أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَأَىٰ",
        "answer": "he saw",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "raā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَدْ رَأَىٰ مِنْ آيَاتِ رَبِّهِ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ",
        "answer": "So have you seen",
        "pcklId": "216",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-aytumu",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 19,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتُمُ اللَّاتَ وَالْعُزَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَرَأَيْتَ",
        "answer": "Did you see",
        "pcklId": "217",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "afara-ayta",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَرَىٰ",
        "answer": "sees",
        "pcklId": "218",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yarā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " أَعِنْدَهُ عِلْمُ الْغَيْبِ فَهُوَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُرَىٰ",
        "answer": "be seen",
        "pcklId": "219",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "yurā",
        "frequency": 328,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ سَعْيَهُ سَوْفَ يُرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 271,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) his Lord",
        "pcklId": "814",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihi",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَدْ رَأَىٰ مِنْ آيَاتِ رَبِّهِ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهِمُ",
        "answer": "their Lord",
        "pcklId": "815",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihimu",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 24,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنْ رَبِّهِمُ الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "816",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "817",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbaka",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ وَاسِعُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "818",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّ",
        "answer": "(is the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "819",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbu",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ رَبُّ الشِّعْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "(of) your Lord",
        "pcklId": "820",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": 980,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ آلَاءِ رَبِّكَ تَتَمَارَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 975,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيَرْضَىٰ",
        "answer": "and approves",
        "pcklId": "31",
        "rootWordId": 561,
        "tlit": "wayarḍā",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 18,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ر ض و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّضِىَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be pleased",
        "waznTlit": "raḍiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 38,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُرِدْ",
        "answer": "he desires",
        "pcklId": "138",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "yurid",
        "frequency": 148,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 139,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُزَكُّوا",
        "answer": "ascribe purity",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 624,
        "tlit": "tuzakkū",
        "frequency": 59,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 26,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُزَكُّوا أَنْفُسَكُمْ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ك و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَكَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to purify",
        "waznTlit": "zakkā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّوْجَيْنِ",
        "answer": "the pairs",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "l-zawjayni",
        "frequency": 81,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 45,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ خَلَقَ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 76,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "زَاغَ",
        "answer": "swerved",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 644,
        "tlit": "zāgha",
        "frequency": 9,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا زَاغَ الْبَصَرُ وَمَا طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز ي غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَاغَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deviate, to turn away, to swerve",
        "waznTlit": "zāgha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَبِيلِهِ",
        "answer": "His Path",
        "pcklId": "160",
        "rootWordId": 656,
        "tlit": "sabīlihi",
        "frequency": 176,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س ب ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the way",
        "waznTlit": "sīn bā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 176,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاسْجُدُوا",
        "answer": "So prostrate",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 659,
        "tlit": "fa-us'judū",
        "frequency": 92,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْجُدُوا لِلَّهِ وَاعْبُدُوا",
        "rootWord": "س ج د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَجَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to prostrate",
        "waznTlit": "sajada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سِدْرَةِ",
        "answer": "(the) Lote Tree",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 672,
        "tlit": "sid'rati",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَ سِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِدْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "lote trees",
        "waznTlit": "sid'rat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السِّدْرَةَ",
        "answer": "the Lote Tree",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 672,
        "tlit": "l-sid'rata",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ يَغْشَى السِّدْرَةَ مَا يَغْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِدْرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "lote trees",
        "waznTlit": "sid'rat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَعَىٰ",
        "answer": "he strives (for)",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "saʿā",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَيْسَ لِلْإِنْسَانِ إِلَّا مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to strive, to run",
        "waznTlit": "saʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَعْيَهُ",
        "answer": "his striving",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 692,
        "tlit": "saʿyahu",
        "frequency": 30,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 40,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ سَعْيَهُ سَوْفَ يُرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س ع ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَعْي",
        "waznEnglish": "and strives",
        "waznTlit": "saʿī",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سُلْطَانٍ",
        "answer": "authority",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 713,
        "tlit": "sul'ṭānin",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا أَسْمَاءٌ سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ مَا أَنْزَلَ اللَّهُ بِهَا مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُلْطَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "surely He (would have) given them power",
        "waznTlit": "sul'ṭān",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 37,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَامِدُونَ",
        "answer": "amuse (yourselves)",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 720,
        "tlit": "sāmidūna",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 61,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْتُمْ سَامِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س م د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س م د",
        "waznEnglish": "amuse (yourselves)",
        "waznTlit": "sīn mīm dāl",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا",
        "answer": "you have named them",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "sammaytumūhā",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا أَسْمَاءٌ سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to name",
        "waznTlit": "sammā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيُسَمُّونَ",
        "answer": "surely they name",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "layusammūna",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to name",
        "waznTlit": "sammā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَسْمَاءٌ",
        "answer": "names",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "asmāon",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا أَسْمَاءٌ سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْم",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "is'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 39,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "the heavens",
        "pcklId": "310",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَمْ مِنْ مَلَكٍ فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "the heavens",
        "pcklId": "311",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلِلَّهِ مَا فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ وَمَا فِي الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 310,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَسْمِيَةَ",
        "answer": "name(s)",
        "pcklId": "359",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "tasmiyata",
        "frequency": 381,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَسْمِيَة",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "tasmiyat",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَسَاءُوا",
        "answer": "do evil",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 737,
        "tlit": "asāū",
        "frequency": 167,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسَاءُوا بِمَا عَمِلُوا",
        "rootWord": "س و أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do evil",
        "waznTlit": "asāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاسْتَوَىٰ",
        "answer": "And he rose",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "fa-is'tawā",
        "frequency": 83,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " ذُو مِرَّةٍ فَاسْتَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱسْتَوَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be equal, to be alike, to establish",
        "waznTlit": "is'tawā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 35,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَدِيدُ",
        "answer": "the (one) mighty",
        "pcklId": "96",
        "rootWordId": 762,
        "tlit": "shadīdu",
        "frequency": 102,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَهُ شَدِيدُ الْقُوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش د د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَدِيد",
        "waznEnglish": "and harden",
        "waznTlit": "shadīd",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 56,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الشِّعْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "(of) Sirius",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 778,
        "tlit": "l-shiʿ'rā",
        "frequency": 40,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 49,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ رَبُّ الشِّعْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش ع ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شِّعْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they realize (it)",
        "waznTlit": "shiʿ'rā",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَفَاعَتُهُمْ",
        "answer": "their intercession",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 782,
        "tlit": "shafāʿatuhum",
        "frequency": 31,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ف ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَفَٰعَة",
        "waznEnglish": "can intercede",
        "waznTlit": "shafāʿat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَشَاءُ",
        "answer": "He wills",
        "pcklId": "210",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "yashāu",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 17,
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ وَيَرْضَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَآءَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to will, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "shāa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 236,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْئًا",
        "answer": "anything",
        "pcklId": "486",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayan",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا إِلَّا مِنْ بَعْدِ أَنْ يَأْذَنَ اللَّهُ لِمَنْ يَشَاءُ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْئًا",
        "answer": "anything",
        "pcklId": "487",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayan",
        "frequency": 519,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 16,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 283,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صَاحِبُكُمْ",
        "answer": "your companion",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "ṣāḥibukum",
        "frequency": 97,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا ضَلَّ صَاحِبُكُمْ وَمَا غَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَاحِب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "ṣāḥib",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 10,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "صُحُفِ",
        "answer": "(the) Scriptures",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 823,
        "tlit": "ṣuḥufi",
        "frequency": 9,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَمْ يُنَبَّأْ بِمَا فِي صُحُفِ مُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صُحُف",
        "waznEnglish": "plates",
        "waznTlit": "ṣuḥuf",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَضْحَكُونَ",
        "answer": "And you laugh",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 881,
        "tlit": "wataḍḥakūna",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 60,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَضْحَكُونَ وَلَا تَبْكُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ض ح ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَحِكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to laugh",
        "waznTlit": "ḍaḥikat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَضْحَكَ",
        "answer": "makes (one) laugh",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 881,
        "tlit": "aḍḥaka",
        "frequency": 10,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 43,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَضْحَكَ وَأَبْكَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ح ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَضْحَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make laugh",
        "waznTlit": "aḍḥaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَّ",
        "answer": "has strayed",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalla",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا ضَلَّ صَاحِبُكُمْ وَمَا غَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go astray, to err, to lose",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضَلَّ",
        "answer": "strays",
        "pcklId": "50",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "ḍalla",
        "frequency": 191,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ضَلَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go astray, to err, to lose",
        "waznTlit": "ḍalla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 53,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "ضِيزَىٰ",
        "answer": "unfair",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 899,
        "tlit": "ḍīzā",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " تِلْكَ إِذًا قِسْمَةٌ ضِيزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ض ي ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ض ي ز",
        "waznEnglish": "unfair",
        "waznTlit": "ḍād yā zāy",
        "waznType": "Adjective",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "طَغَىٰ",
        "answer": "it transgressed",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "ṭaghā",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 17,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا زَاغَ الْبَصَرُ وَمَا طَغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to transgress, to overflow",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaghā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "answer": "and more rebellious",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 913,
        "tlit": "wa-aṭghā",
        "frequency": 39,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَوْمَ نُوحٍ مِنْ قَبْلُ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا هُمْ أَظْلَمَ وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ط غ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَطْغَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "transgress",
        "waznTlit": "aṭghā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَظْلَمَ",
        "answer": "more unjust",
        "pcklId": "125",
        "rootWordId": 942,
        "tlit": "aẓlama",
        "frequency": 315,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَوْمَ نُوحٍ مِنْ قَبْلُ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا هُمْ أَظْلَمَ وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَظْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "[you] have wronged",
        "waznTlit": "aẓlam",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الظَّنَّ",
        "answer": "assumption",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "l-ẓana",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 17,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَمَا تَهْوَى الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنّ",
        "waznEnglish": "believe",
        "waznTlit": "ẓann",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الظَّنَّ",
        "answer": "assumption",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "l-ẓana",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لَهُمْ بِهِ مِنْ عِلْمٍ إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنّ",
        "waznEnglish": "believe",
        "waznTlit": "ẓann",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الظَّنَّ",
        "answer": "the assumption",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "l-ẓana",
        "frequency": 69,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنّ",
        "waznEnglish": "believe",
        "waznTlit": "ẓann",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاعْبُدُوا",
        "answer": "and worship (Him)",
        "pcklId": "112",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "wa-uʿ'budū",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 62,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَاسْجُدُوا لِلَّهِ وَاعْبُدُوا",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبَدَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabada",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 122,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَبْدِهِ",
        "answer": "His slave",
        "pcklId": "254",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿabdihi",
        "frequency": 275,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَوْحَىٰ إِلَىٰ عَبْدِهِ مَا أَوْحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 131,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْجَبُونَ",
        "answer": "you wonder",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 959,
        "tlit": "taʿjabūna",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 59,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَمِنْ هَٰذَا الْحَدِيثِ تَعْجَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَجِبُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to wonder, to be amazed, to be astonished",
        "waznTlit": "ʿajibu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَعْرِضْ",
        "answer": "So turn away",
        "pcklId": "40",
        "rootWordId": 975,
        "tlit": "fa-aʿriḍ",
        "frequency": 79,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "ع ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْرَضَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn away",
        "waznTlit": "aʿraḍa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 32,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَعْطَىٰ",
        "answer": "And gave",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1004,
        "tlit": "wa-aʿṭā",
        "frequency": 14,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَعْطَىٰ قَلِيلًا وَأَكْدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْطَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "aʿṭā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلَّمَهُ",
        "answer": "Has taught him",
        "pcklId": "417",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿallamahu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَهُ شَدِيدُ الْقُوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to teach",
        "waznTlit": "ʿallama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 41,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "knows best",
        "pcklId": "451",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 8,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "knows best",
        "pcklId": "452",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 14,
        "arabicAyah": " وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "(is) most knowing about you",
        "pcklId": "453",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعْلَمُ",
        "answer": "knows best",
        "pcklId": "454",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "aʿlamu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 29,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُزَكُّوا أَنْفُسَكُمْ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlam",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِلْمٍ",
        "answer": "knowledge",
        "pcklId": "652",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿil'min",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا لَهُمْ بِهِ مِنْ عِلْمٍ إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِلْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿil'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 105,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعِلْمِ",
        "answer": "knowledge",
        "pcklId": "653",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿil'mi",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " ذَٰلِكَ مَبْلَغُهُمْ مِنَ الْعِلْمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِلْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿil'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 105,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِلْمُ",
        "answer": "(the) knowledge",
        "pcklId": "654",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿil'mu",
        "frequency": 854,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَعِنْدَهُ عِلْمُ الْغَيْبِ فَهُوَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِلْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿil'm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 105,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "the highest",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "l-aʿlā",
        "frequency": 70,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 7,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَهُوَ بِالْأُفُقِ الْأَعْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَعْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "aʿlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَمِلُوا",
        "answer": "they have done",
        "pcklId": "246",
        "rootWordId": 1022,
        "tlit": "ʿamilū",
        "frequency": 360,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 31,
        "wordnum": 12,
        "arabicAyah": " لِيَجْزِيَ الَّذِينَ أَسَاءُوا بِمَا عَمِلُوا",
        "rootWord": "ع م ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَمِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do, to work",
        "waznTlit": "ʿamila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 276,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَ",
        "answer": "Near",
        "pcklId": "143",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿinda",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَ سِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدَهَا",
        "answer": "Near it",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindahā",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 15,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَهَا جَنَّةُ الْمَأْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَعِنْدَهُ",
        "answer": "Is with him",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "aʿindahu",
        "frequency": 201,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَعِنْدَهُ عِلْمُ الْغَيْبِ فَهُوَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)",
        "waznFreq": 197,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "عَادًا",
        "answer": "Aad",
        "pcklId": "55",
        "rootWordId": 1035,
        "tlit": "ʿādan",
        "frequency": 63,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ أَهْلَكَ عَادًا الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَاد",
        "waznEnglish": "repeated",
        "waznTlit": "ʿād",
        "waznType": "Proper noun",
        "waznFreq": 24,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَغْشَى",
        "answer": "covered",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "yaghshā",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " إِذْ يَغْشَى السِّدْرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشِيَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَغْشَىٰ",
        "answer": "covers",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "yaghshā",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 16,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا يَغْشَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشِيَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَغَشَّاهَا",
        "answer": "So covered them",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "faghashāhā",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَغَشَّاهَا مَا غَشَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غَشَّىٰ",
        "answer": "covered",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "ghashā",
        "frequency": 29,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 54,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَغَشَّاهَا مَا غَشَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "answer": "(in) forgiveness",
        "pcklId": "225",
        "rootWordId": 1071,
        "tlit": "l-maghfirati",
        "frequency": 234,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 11,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ وَاسِعُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ف ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّغْفِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "We will forgive",
        "waznTlit": "maghfirat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَغْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "enriches",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "aghnā",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَغْنَىٰ وَأَقْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to prosper",
        "waznTlit": "aghnā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 15,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُغْنِي",
        "answer": "will avail",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "tugh'nī",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَمْ مِنْ مَلَكٍ فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُغْنِي",
        "answer": "avail",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "yugh'nī",
        "frequency": 73,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 28,
        "wordnum": 13,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَإِنَّ الظَّنَّ لَا يُغْنِي مِنَ الْحَقِّ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 28,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "غَوَىٰ",
        "answer": "has he erred",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1092,
        "tlit": "ghawā",
        "frequency": 22,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 2,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا ضَلَّ صَاحِبُكُمْ وَمَا غَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to err, to go astray",
        "waznTlit": "ghawā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْغَيْبِ",
        "answer": "(of) the unseen",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 1093,
        "tlit": "l-ghaybi",
        "frequency": 60,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 35,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَعِنْدَهُ عِلْمُ الْغَيْبِ فَهُوَ يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "غ ي ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَيْب",
        "waznEnglish": "backbite",
        "waznTlit": "ghayb",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 49,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفُؤَادُ",
        "answer": "the heart",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1098,
        "tlit": "l-fuādu",
        "frequency": 16,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا كَذَبَ الْفُؤَادُ مَا رَأَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ف أ د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف أ د",
        "waznEnglish": "their hearts",
        "waznTlit": "fā hamza dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 16,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْفَوَاحِشَ",
        "answer": "and the immoralities",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1110,
        "tlit": "wal-fawāḥisha",
        "frequency": 24,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ح ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰحِشَة",
        "waznEnglish": "immorality",
        "waznTlit": "fāḥishat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 17,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلُ",
        "answer": "before",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablu",
        "frequency": 294,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَوْمَ نُوحٍ مِنْ قَبْلُ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا هُمْ أَظْلَمَ وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 242,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قِسْمَةٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a division",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "qis'matun",
        "frequency": 33,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 22,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " تِلْكَ إِذًا قِسْمَةٌ ضِيزَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِسْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "distribute",
        "waznTlit": "qis'mat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَلِيلًا",
        "answer": "a little",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1225,
        "tlit": "qalīlan",
        "frequency": 76,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَعْطَىٰ قَلِيلًا وَأَكْدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) little",
        "waznTlit": "qalīl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)",
        "waznFreq": 70,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَقْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "and suffices",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1239,
        "tlit": "wa-aqnā",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 48,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَغْنَىٰ وَأَقْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق ن ي",
        "waznEnglish": "and suffices",
        "waznTlit": "qāf nūn yā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَابَ",
        "answer": "(at) a distance",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1241,
        "tlit": "qāba",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَ قَابَ قَوْسَيْنِ أَوْ أَدْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق و ب",
        "waznEnglish": "(at) a distance",
        "waznTlit": "qāf wāw bā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْسَيْنِ",
        "answer": "(of) two bow-(lengths)",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1243,
        "tlit": "qawsayni",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَ قَابَ قَوْسَيْنِ أَوْ أَدْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق و س",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) two bow-(lengths)",
        "waznTlit": "qāf wāw sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَوْمَ",
        "answer": "And (the) people",
        "pcklId": "466",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "waqawma",
        "frequency": 660,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَوْمَ نُوحٍ مِنْ قَبْلُ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا هُمْ أَظْلَمَ وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 383,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقُوَىٰ",
        "answer": "(in) power",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 1247,
        "tlit": "l-quwā",
        "frequency": 42,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 5,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " عَلَّمَهُ شَدِيدُ الْقُوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُوَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) All-Strong",
        "waznTlit": "quwwat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 30,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the Greatest",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kub'rā",
        "frequency": 161,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 18,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَقَدْ رَأَىٰ مِنْ آيَاتِ رَبِّهِ الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَبَائِرَ",
        "answer": "great",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "kabāira",
        "frequency": 161,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَبِيرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kabīrat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَكْدَىٰ",
        "answer": "and withheld",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1262,
        "tlit": "wa-akdā",
        "frequency": 1,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 34,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَعْطَىٰ قَلِيلًا وَأَكْدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك د ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to withhold",
        "waznTlit": "kāf dāl yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَبَ",
        "answer": "lied",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhaba",
        "frequency": 282,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 11,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا كَذَبَ الْفُؤَادُ مَا رَأَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to lie",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَاشِفَةٌ",
        "answer": "any remover",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1275,
        "tlit": "kāshifatun",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لَهَا مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ كَاشِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ش ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَاشِفَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and He would remove",
        "waznTlit": "kāshifat",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَكَانَ",
        "answer": "And was",
        "pcklId": "1236",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "fakāna",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 9,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَكَانَ قَابَ قَوْسَيْنِ أَوْ أَدْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they were",
        "pcklId": "1237",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": 1390,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 52,
        "wordnum": 6,
        "arabicAyah": " وَقَوْمَ نُوحٍ مِنْ قَبْلُ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا هُمْ أَظْلَمَ وَأَطْغَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 1358,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّمَمَ",
        "answer": "the small faults",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1351,
        "tlit": "l-lamama",
        "frequency": 4,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " الَّذِينَ يَجْتَنِبُونَ كَبَائِرَ الْإِثْمِ وَالْفَوَاحِشَ إِلَّا اللَّمَمَ",
        "rootWord": "ل م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَّمَم",
        "waznEnglish": "Bring forward",
        "waznTlit": "lamam",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْسَ",
        "answer": "is not",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "laysa",
        "frequency": 89,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 39,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَيْسَ لِلْإِنْسَانِ إِلَّا مَا سَعَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 89,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْسَ",
        "answer": "Not is",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "laysa",
        "frequency": 89,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 58,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " لَيْسَ لَهَا مِنْ دُونِ اللَّهِ كَاشِفَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 89,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مِرَّةٍ",
        "answer": "Possessor of soundness",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1385,
        "tlit": "mirratin",
        "frequency": 35,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 6,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " ذُو مِرَّةٍ فَاسْتَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِرَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "passed",
        "waznTlit": "mirrat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَفَتُمَارُونَهُ",
        "answer": "Then will you dispute with him",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1387,
        "tlit": "afatumārūnahu",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 12,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَتُمَارُونَهُ عَلَىٰ مَا يَرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَارَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dispute, to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "tamāra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَتَمَارَىٰ",
        "answer": "will you doubt",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1387,
        "tlit": "tatamārā",
        "frequency": 20,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 55,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَبِأَيِّ آلَاءِ رَبِّكَ تَتَمَارَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَارَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dispute, to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "tamāra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 4,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "مَلَكٍ",
        "answer": "(the) Angels",
        "pcklId": "139",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "malakin",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 26,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَكَمْ مِنْ مَلَكٍ فِي السَّمَاوَاتِ لَا تُغْنِي شَفَاعَتُهُمْ شَيْئًا",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَلَائِكَةَ",
        "answer": "the Angels",
        "pcklId": "140",
        "rootWordId": 1415,
        "tlit": "l-malāikata",
        "frequency": 206,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 27,
        "wordnum": 7,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الَّذِينَ لَا يُؤْمِنُونَ بِالْآخِرَةِ لَيُسَمُّونَ الْمَلَائِكَةَ تَسْمِيَةَ الْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَلَك",
        "waznEnglish": "possesses",
        "waznTlit": "malak",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 88,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمَنَّىٰ",
        "answer": "he wishes",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1420,
        "tlit": "tamannā",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 24,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لِلْإِنْسَانِ مَا تَمَنَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَمَنَّىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to wish",
        "waznTlit": "tamannā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تُمْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "it is emitted",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1420,
        "tlit": "tum'nā",
        "frequency": 21,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ إِذَا تُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُمْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to emit",
        "waznTlit": "yum'nā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَاتَ",
        "answer": "causes death",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "amāta",
        "frequency": 165,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 44,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ هُوَ أَمَاتَ وَأَحْيَا",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause death",
        "waznTlit": "amāta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 21,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنَبَّأْ",
        "answer": "he was informed",
        "pcklId": "36",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "yunabba",
        "frequency": 160,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 36,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْ لَمْ يُنَبَّأْ بِمَا فِي صُحُفِ مُوسَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَّأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to inform",
        "waznTlit": "nabba-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 46,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالنَّجْمِ",
        "answer": "By the star",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1444,
        "tlit": "wal-najmi",
        "frequency": 13,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّجْمِ إِذَا هَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ج م",
        "waznEnglish": "the stars",
        "waznTlit": "nūn jīm mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 13,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَذِيرٌ",
        "answer": "(is) a warner",
        "pcklId": "91",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "nadhīrun",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نَذِيرٌ مِنَ النُّذُرِ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النُّذُرِ",
        "answer": "the warners",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "l-nudhuri",
        "frequency": 130,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 56,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " هَٰذَا نَذِيرٌ مِنَ النُّذُرِ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "nadhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 58,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْزَلَ",
        "answer": "has Allah sent down",
        "pcklId": "240",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "anzala",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 9,
        "arabicAyah": " سَمَّيْتُمُوهَا أَنْتُمْ وَآبَاؤُكُمْ مَا أَنْزَلَ اللَّهُ بِهَا مِنْ سُلْطَانٍ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 183,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نَزْلَةً",
        "answer": "(in) descent",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "nazlatan",
        "frequency": 293,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 13,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ رَآهُ نَزْلَةً أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَزْلَة",
        "waznEnglish": "it descended",
        "waznTlit": "nazlat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 1,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْشَأَكُمْ",
        "answer": "He produced you",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "ansha-akum",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 16,
        "arabicAyah": " هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنشَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to produce, to raise",
        "waznTlit": "ansha-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 20,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّشْأَةَ",
        "answer": "(is) the bringing forth",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1470,
        "tlit": "l-nashata",
        "frequency": 28,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 47,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ عَلَيْهِ النَّشْأَةَ الْأُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّشْأَة",
        "waznEnglish": "is brought up",
        "waznTlit": "nashat",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "نُطْفَةٍ",
        "answer": "a semen-drop",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1485,
        "tlit": "nuṭ'fatin",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 46,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ نُطْفَةٍ إِذَا تُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ط ف",
        "waznEnglish": "a minute quantity of semen",
        "waznTlit": "nūn ṭā fā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يَنْطِقُ",
        "answer": "he speaks",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1486,
        "tlit": "yanṭiqu",
        "frequency": 12,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَنْطِقُ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَنطِقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to speak",
        "waznTlit": "yanṭiqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "answer": "the(ir) souls",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "l-anfusu",
        "frequency": 298,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 20,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَمَا تَهْوَى الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 295,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْفُسَكُمْ",
        "answer": "(to) yourselves",
        "pcklId": "269",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "anfusakum",
        "frequency": 298,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 27,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُزَكُّوا أَنْفُسَكُمْ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 295,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "answer": "(of) the utmost boundary",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "l-muntahā",
        "frequency": 56,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 14,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " عِنْدَ سِدْرَةِ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنتَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and forbidding",
        "waznTlit": "muntahā",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "answer": "(is) the final goal",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1526,
        "tlit": "l-muntahā",
        "frequency": 56,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 42,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّ إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ الْمُنْتَهَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ه ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنتَهَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and forbidding",
        "waznTlit": "muntahā",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 3,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "answer": "is guided",
        "pcklId": "183",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "ih'tadā",
        "frequency": 316,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 30,
        "wordnum": 16,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنْ ضَلَّ عَنْ سَبِيلِهِ وَهُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اهْتَدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱهْتَدَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be guided",
        "waznTlit": "ih'tadā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 40,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْهُدَىٰ",
        "answer": "the guidance",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 1547,
        "tlit": "l-hudā",
        "frequency": 316,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 25,
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ مِنْ رَبِّهِمُ الْهُدَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هُدًى",
        "waznEnglish": "Guide us",
        "waznTlit": "hudan",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 85,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "answer": "destroyed",
        "pcklId": "49",
        "rootWordId": 1559,
        "tlit": "ahlaka",
        "frequency": 68,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 50,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنَّهُ أَهْلَكَ عَادًا الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "ahlaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 51,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "هَوَىٰ",
        "answer": "it goes down",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "hawā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 1,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالنَّجْمِ إِذَا هَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire",
        "waznTlit": "hawā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَهْوَى",
        "answer": "desire",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "tahwā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 23,
        "wordnum": 19,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ يَتَّبِعُونَ إِلَّا الظَّنَّ وَمَا تَهْوَى الْأَنْفُسُ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire",
        "waznTlit": "hawā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْوَىٰ",
        "answer": "He overthrew",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "ahwā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 53,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْمُؤْتَفِكَةَ أَهْوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَوَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to desire",
        "waznTlit": "hawā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 8,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْهَوَىٰ",
        "answer": "the desire",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1571,
        "tlit": "l-hawā",
        "frequency": 38,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 3,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا يَنْطِقُ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "هَوَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "desire",
        "waznTlit": "hawā",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 11,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "يُوحَىٰ",
        "answer": "revealed",
        "pcklId": "67",
        "rootWordId": 1595,
        "tlit": "yūḥā",
        "frequency": 78,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هُوَ إِلَّا وَحْيٌ يُوحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ح ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْحَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reveal, to inspire",
        "waznTlit": "awḥā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَوْحَىٰ",
        "answer": "So he revealed",
        "pcklId": "68",
        "rootWordId": 1595,
        "tlit": "fa-awḥā",
        "frequency": 78,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 1,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَوْحَىٰ إِلَىٰ عَبْدِهِ",
        "rootWord": "و ح ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْحَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reveal, to inspire",
        "waznTlit": "awḥā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوْحَىٰ",
        "answer": "he revealed",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1595,
        "tlit": "awḥā",
        "frequency": 78,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 10,
        "wordnum": 5,
        "arabicAyah": " مَا أَوْحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ح ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْحَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reveal, to inspire",
        "waznTlit": "awḥā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)",
        "waznFreq": 72,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَحْيٌ",
        "answer": "a revelation",
        "pcklId": "77",
        "rootWordId": 1595,
        "tlit": "waḥyun",
        "frequency": 78,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 4,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هُوَ إِلَّا وَحْيٌ يُوحَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ح ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَحْى",
        "waznEnglish": "We reveal it",
        "waznTlit": "waḥ",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 6,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَزِرُ",
        "answer": "will bear",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1605,
        "tlit": "taziru",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 2,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَّا تَزِرُ وَازِرَةٌ وِزْرَ أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَزِرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to bear",
        "waznTlit": "yaziru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)",
        "waznFreq": 7,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وِزْرَ",
        "answer": "(the) burden",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1605,
        "tlit": "wiz'ra",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَّا تَزِرُ وَازِرَةٌ وِزْرَ أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وِزْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bear",
        "waznTlit": "wiz'r",
        "waznType": "Noun",
        "waznFreq": 12,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَازِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "a bearer of burdens",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1605,
        "tlit": "wāziratun",
        "frequency": 27,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 38,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَّا تَزِرُ وَازِرَةٌ وِزْرَ أُخْرَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَازِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they bear",
        "waznTlit": "wāzirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 5,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاسِعُ",
        "answer": "(is) vast",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1609,
        "tlit": "wāsiʿu",
        "frequency": 32,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 10,
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ رَبَّكَ وَاسِعُ الْمَغْفِرَةِ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِكُمْ إِذْ أَنْشَأَكُمْ مِنَ الْأَرْضِ",
        "rootWord": "و س ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَٰسِع",
        "waznEnglish": "Extends",
        "waznTlit": "wāsiʿ",
        "waznType": "Active participle",
        "waznFreq": 9,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "وَفَّىٰ",
        "answer": "fulfilled",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1633,
        "tlit": "waffā",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 37,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِبْرَاهِيمَ الَّذِي وَفَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ف ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَفَّىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pay in full, to fulfill",
        "waznTlit": "waffā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)",
        "waznFreq": 18,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوْفَىٰ",
        "answer": "the fullest",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 1633,
        "tlit": "l-awfā",
        "frequency": 66,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 41,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ يُجْزَاهُ الْجَزَاءَ الْأَوْفَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ف ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْفَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "will be repaid in full",
        "waznTlit": "awfā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)",
        "waznFreq": 2,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "اتَّقَىٰ",
        "answer": "fears",
        "pcklId": "166",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "ittaqā",
        "frequency": 258,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 32,
        "wordnum": 31,
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا تُزَكُّوا أَنْفُسَكُمْ هُوَ أَعْلَمُ بِمَنِ اتَّقَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّقَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be righteous, to fear (Allah)",
        "waznTlit": "ittaqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)",
        "waznFreq": 166,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "turns away",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "tawallā",
        "frequency": 232,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 29,
        "wordnum": 4,
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَعْرِضْ عَنْ مَنْ تَوَلَّىٰ عَنْ ذِكْرِنَا وَلَمْ يُرِدْ إِلَّا الْحَيَاةَ الدُّنْيَا",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    },
    {
        "question": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "turned away",
        "pcklId": "93",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "tawallā",
        "frequency": 232,
        "surahnum": 53,
        "ayahnum": 33,
        "wordnum": 3,
        "arabicAyah": " أَفَرَأَيْتَ الَّذِي تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)",
        "waznFreq": 78,
        "hasRootWord": true
    }
]; 
export default words;